Worlds collide.
The Flash is a action, science fiction, adventure
film directed by Andy Muschietti.
When his attempt to save his family inadvertently alters the future, Barry Allen becomes trapped in a
reality in which General Zod has returned and there are no Super Heroes to turn to.
In order to save the world that he is in and return to the future that
he knows, Barry's only hope is to race for his life.
But will making the ultimate sacrifice be enough to reset the universe?
Barry Allen / The Flash, played by Ezra Miller.
Kara Zor-El / Supergirl, played by Sasha Calle.
Bruce Wayne / Batman, played by Michael Keaton.
General Zod, played by Michael Shannon.
Henry Allen, played by Ron Livingston.
Nora Allen, played by Maribel Verdú.
The Flash is a 2023 American superhero film based on the DC
Comics character Barry Allen / The Flash.
Directed by Andy Muschietti from a screenplay by Christina Hodson and a story by the writing team of John Francis Daley
and Jonathan Goldstein alongside Joby Harold, it is the 13th film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
Ezra Miller stars as Barry Allen, who travels back in time to prevent his
mother's death and becomes stranded in an alternate past.
Sasha Calle also stars in her film debut, alongside Michael Shannon, Ron
Livingston, Maribel Verdú, Kiersey Clemons, Antje Traue, and Michael Keaton.
Barbara Muschietti and Michael Disco produced the
film for DC Films and Warner Bros.
Development on a film featuring the Flash began in the late 1980s, with various iterations
planned through 2014, when it was redeveloped for the DCEU and Miller was cast.
Multiple writers and directors were attached over the following years, with Seth Grahame-Smith, Rick
Famuyiwa, Daley, and Goldstein all departing the project over creative differences with the studios.
Muschietti and Hodson became involved in July 2019, and
pre-production began in January 2020.
Influenced by the 2011 comic book storyline Flashpoint, the film explores the multiverse and features other DC characters, such as Calle's Supergirl and multiple
versions of Batman, particularly Keaton's portrayal from the films Batman (1989) and Batman Returns (1992), while others were digitally included.
Filming lasted from April to October 2021 at Warner Bros.
Studios Leavesden and on location throughout the United Kingdom.
The film's ending was altered several times during post-production due to
changes in DC's wider plans under different studio leadership.
The Flash premiered at Grauman's Chinese Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 12, 2023, and was released in the
United States on June 16, following multiple delays caused by the director changes and the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its humor, action
sequences, and performances, but criticized the visual effects and third act.
It was also a box-office bomb, grossing $271.4 million
worldwide against a budget of $200–220 million.
Its box office performance was attributed to factors such as Miller's legal issues and controversies, the franchise's imminent
reboot with the DC Universe (DCU), superhero fatigue, and the film's mixed reception and marketing practices.
The film explores themes of secret identity, superhero,
time travel, based on comic, superhuman.
The tone is thought_provoking.